Three visionary tales. One unforgettable place.
The House is a animation, drama, comedy film directed by Paloma Baeza.
Across different eras, a poor family, an anxious developer and a fed-up landlady
become tied to the same mysterious house in this animated dark comedy.
Mabel (voice), played by Mia Goth.
Raymond (voice), played by Matthew Goode.
Penelope (voice), played by Claudie Blakley.
Isobel (voice), played by Eleanor De Swaef-Roels.
Mr. Thomas (voice), played by Mark Heap.
Great Aunt Eleanor (voice), played by Stephanie Cole.
The House is a 2022 British stop-motion adult animated
anthology television special created by Enda Walsh.
The production is divided into three chapters telling different stories spanning different worlds, interior designs, and characters (consisting of humans,
anthropomorphic rodents and insects, and felines) in the same house; each story deals with themes of madness, wealth, and the pursuit of true happiness.
Originally announced as an anthology miniseries, owing to its
short length, it became a television special.
Produced for Netflix by Nexus Studios in London, it tells three chapters respectively directed by the duo of Emma de Swaef and Marc James Roels, Niki Lindroth von
Bahr, and Paloma Baeza; the directors are credited with the story of their respective segments, with Johannes Nyholm as co-writer for the second.
The film explores themes of dark comedy, surreal, stop motion.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.